Mr. Isaac Kobby Anni



MASTER'S RESEARCH-ABSTRACT

"Structual approach to credit risk modeling"

I apply stochastic models of a company's value to investigate the likelihood credit default events where the value of the company falls below the level of bankruptcy. My research considers exact solutions using the models of Merton and Black-Cox, as well as the role of simulation in Python in generalising this framework outside of those models. This research is in progress and results shall be defended by February, 2022 as well as publication.

BACHELOR'S RESEARCH-ABSTRACT

"Effects of capital structure on the profitability of financial firms listed on the Ghana Stock Exchange"

My research investigated the audited financial statements of financial institutions listed on the GSE by examining the spread of their capital structure and extracting important information for determining the patterns of their profitability. The research revealed significantly, that the spread of firm's value between equity and debt plays major role in company's profitability.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CURRENT, FROM AUGUST 2021 (PT)

Obertys Technologies *Data Scientist (Intern)*

As part of my Master's cooperative program I begun as a Data Scientist intern with Obertys where I work on enterprise credit risk modeling using machine learning techniques. My team includes web/mobile developers who use models with mobile/web applications for financial institutions. The focus is on practical outcomes and applications in industry.

SEP 2019 - AUG 2020 (PT)

Advans Ghana Savings and Loans Limited Legal Administrative Assistant

This position was a mandatory national service after my undergraduate studies. I joined the legal department where I worked on legal documents that involved loan acquisition or loan recovery. I prepared documents like mortgages, debentures, court letters as well as mediating bank supervision regulation documents between the company and the central Bank of Ghana.

JUN 2018 – AUG 2018 (PT)

Newmont GoldCorp Corporation, Africa Office-Accra Summer Intern-Risk Management

In this summer internship I was tasked with studying energy power rates and updating the system with the details of timely changes using Microsoft Excel. I carried along with administrative duties like power bill analysis, reviewing insurance policies and informing deadlines.

REFERENCES

P.O. Box 1418, Joal KM 2 AIMS Senegal, +221 (77) 571-2158

isaac.k.anni@aims-senegal.org

Personal Blog
GitHub
LinkedIn

EDUCATION

2020-2022 Master of Science

IN PROGRESS

Mathematical Sciences(Big Data option)

African Institute of Mathematical Sciences

2015 – 2019 Bachelor of Science

second class upper division Financial Mathematics

University for Development Studies

AWARDS

2020 Masters Scholarship

African Institute of Mathematical Sciences

COMPUTER SKILLS

BASIC Javascript, React, Hadoop,

SQL, MongoDB, Postgres

INTERMEDIATE R, LATEX

Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, Linux, Mac

Computer Hardware & Support

ADVANCED Python; TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch

CERTIFICATIONS

JUL, 2021 TensorFlow Developer Certificate-Udemy

JUL, 2021 Python and ML for financial analysis-Udemy

MAY, 2021 Deep learning and Computer vision-Udemy

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

2021 Oral Presentations at the AIMS Senegal

2020 Project presentation at Advans Ghana Savings & Loans Ltd

2019 Thesis defense at the University for Development Studies

SKILLS

Goal Oriented

I believe in action over long-winded discussions. I listen to everyone's viewpoints and use my judgement to immediately act based on consensus to achieve goals quickly and efficiently.

Physical Dexterity

I am a very strong young man that sits by my computer until a bug is debugged and solution is made reasonable.

Passionate

I have been interested in applied mathematics and relativity from my secondary school age. Further studies has cemented this interest into a passion. I greatly enjoy carrying

Prof. Des Johnston

POSITION Professor

EMPLOYER School of Mathematical and Computer Sciences (MACS)

Heriot-Watt University, UK.

EMAIL D.A.Johnston@hw.ac.uk

MOBILE +441-31-451-3255

Dr. Conall Kelly

POSITION Director/Lecturer

EMPLOYER School of Mathematical Sciences

University College Cork, Ireland.

EMAIL conall.kelly@ucc.ie MOBILE +353-2I-490-3000 out data science related projects with potential practical applications.

HOBBIES

- · Table tennis
- Football
- Fitness